Guide to the New York University Archives Audiovisual Collection AV
New York University Archives
- Audiovisual Recordings
  - Voices of the Encounter (tapes 1 and 2), undated; AV3483 (Box 95, Item 3483)
    This tape is related to materials in RG 9.5.1, Records of the Humanities Council.
  - God's Trombones (tapes 1 and 2), undated; AV3491 (Box 96, Item 3491)
  - Voices of the Encounter (the Columbus legacy), AV3520; Berzins, Zane (Box 97, Item 3520)
  - Martin Cherlasky Lecture (tape 2 of 3 and tape 3 of 3), undated; AV3603 (Box 99, Item 3603)
    Dr. David Kessler lectured at this event.
    This tape is related to materials in RG 33, Records of the Robert F. Wagner School of Public Service.
  - "Dr. L. Jay Oliva/NYU" on Fox on Education, 18 December 1996; AV3858 (Box 123, Cassette 3858)
  - New York 1 news broadcast about L. Jay Oliva (2 tapes), undated; AV3875; NY1; 1 VHS (Box 124, Cassette 3875)
    This program was originally broadcast on NY1's "Hourly News" program and rights to the content may reside with that network.
  - Federal Energy Office: U.S. Energy Policy and You, AV3877; Sawhill, John C., 1936- (Box 124, Item 3877)
  - Lou Dobbs interview with L. Jay Oliva (2 tapes), 1 February 1997; AV3891; Dobbs, Lou; 1 VHS (Box 124, Cassette AV3891)
    This program was originally broadcast on CNN and rights to the content may reside with that network.
  - A Special Tribute to Laurence Tisch, 1999; AV3896; Tisch School of the Arts; 1 VHS 14:00 (Box Shared University Archives 112, Dvd 9:9)
    A brief biographical documentary honoring Lawrence "Larry" Tisch, featuring testimonials from friends and colleagues.
    Gallo, Philip; Guarino, Elisa; Sills, Beverly; Tisch family; New York University. Office of Media Production; Oliva, L. Jay (Lawrence Jay), 1933-2014; Tisch, Laurence, 1923-2003
  - NYU Lewis L. and Loretta Brennan Ireland House Dedication, 1993 April 26; AV3919 (Box 107, Cassette 3919)
    Glucksman Ireland House
  - New York University: The One Hundred Fifty-ninth Commencement Exercises, 1991 May 16; AV3925; New York University; Guarino, Elisa; 1 VHS (Box 108, Cassette 3925)
    Copies available
    Digitized copy available. Please ask at Archives.
    New York University. Office of Public Affairs
  - Inauguration of L. Jay Oliva, 21 November 1991; AV3929 (Box 123, Cassette 3929)
    VHS
  - NYU Lewis L. and Loretta Brennan Ireland House Dedication, 1993 April 26; AV3934 (Box 108, Cassette 3934)
  - Recruitment: David B. Kriser Center, undated; AV3968 (Box 110, Item 3968)
  - Development: David B. Kriser Center, undated; AV3969 (Box 110, Item 3969)
  - Michael Harrington and Today's Other America (tape 1 of 2), undated; AV4268 (Box 116, Item 4268)
  - Michael Harrington and Today's Other America (tape 2 of 2), undated; AV4269 (Box 116, Item 4269)
  - "TV Commercials as a Communications Environment", 10 December 1976; AV4447; Postman, Neil; 1 Digital_Betacam 30 minutes (Box 118, Cassette 4447, Box Shared University Archives 108, Item 37, Box Shared University Archives 116, Item 4)
    This footage is from the Sunrise Semester Education Television Series.
    Access copy available on DVD: ACCESS 13:4
  - Marshall McLuhan untitled, AV4448; 1 videocassettes (Box 118, Reel 4448)
    The video quality of this disc is grainy and the volume is makes it difficult to hear exactly what people are saying The setting is a lecture hall Where McLuhan, Nevitt, and various other people are seated facing an audience. In his discussion there is a reference to being at a conference at the School of Dentistry but nothing is truly specified. The men, mainly McLuhan, discuss how environment effects and is effected by technology while the actual technology is incidental. They further talk about technological breakthroughs and how humans perceive it. Intellectual decline from over stimulation from technology creating a "goal-less" child who is more interested in role playing rather than true decision making thanks to television and radio. Most of the discussion is based on McLuahn's "Laws of Media" which is a four part tetrad of things that share an "interlocking nature" when humans consume media. The four parts are Enhance, Reverse, Retrieve, Obsolescence. The film cuts out frequently and ends abruptly.
    Access copy available on CD: ACCESS 1:22
  - "The TV Frame", AV4449; Postman, Neil; 1 Digital_Betacam 28:30 (Box 118, Cassette 4449, Box Shared University Archives 108, Item 39, Box Shared University Archives 116, Item 6)
    This footage was part of the Sunrise Semester Education Television Series.
    Access copy available on DVD: ACCESS 13:6.
  - "Television News as a Communications Form", 17 December 1976; AV4450; Postman, Neil; 1 Digital_Betacam 29:15 (Box 118, Cassette 4450, Box Shared University Archives 108, Item 38, Box Shared University Archives 116, Item 5)
    This footage is part of the Sunrise Semester Education Television Series.
    Access copy available on DVD: ACCESS 13:5.
  - Marshall McLuhan Ecology Program, AV4451; 1 reel (Box 118, Reel 4451)
    Access copy available on CD: ACCESS 1:21
    No title of event given or visible. The video quality of this disk is clear and the people speaking within the room are relatively easy to hear and comprehend especially when McLuhan speaks.The tape starts in the middle of a group discussion. The setting is in an office with a large table. The audience participates, asking McLuhan questions and receiving answers from him. The majority of the discussion is based on McLuhan's "Laws of Media" which is a four part tetrad of things that share an "interlocking nature" when humans consume media. The four parts are Enhance, Reverse, Retrieve, Obsolescence. His discussion raises concern on mans responsibility for technologies and its effect on humans. He argues that we need studies about technology in order to shape them properly for consumption. Part of his argument is about adverting in the American home as opposed to foreign advertising which is much less prevalent in private lives. He also discusses the effects of politicians becoming visually and verbally known by the general public. The discussion ends with the conclusion that our current media is an "open game" meaning that nothing is finalized. McLuhan concludes that he does not believe there is a solidified answer to his questions. Instead he views it as a continued exploration. The film ends with questions from the audience where McLuhan fields questions, takes business cards, and hands back his portable mic he was using.
  - Flying Saucer Mystery, 1950; AV5044 (Box 121, Item 5044)
  - An Open Mind - Discussions with Dean John Sexton, November 18, 1998 & December 15, 1999; AV5135; Approx. 60 minutes
    Two episodes of "The Open Mind" with Richard D. Heffner, Dowling Professor of Communications and Public Policy at Rutgers University. Both episodes feature conversations with Dean of NYU School of Law, John Sexton.
    - Original Recording (Box 123, Vhs 5135)
    - Access Copy (Box Shared University Archives 113, Dvd 10:28)
  - Three Steps to Start, circa 1950s-1970s; AV5141; New York University (Box n/a, Reel 5141)
    This film is about adult education.
  - A Child Went Forth, circa 1950s-1970s; AV5142; New York University; Leaf, Munro, 1905-1976; 1 film reels (Box n/a, Reel 5142)
  - Prof. Raiken's class/Gallatin promo/Gallatin tape 13, undated; AV5144 (Box To be processed, Reel 5144, Box Shared University Archives 116, Item 55)
  - Unknown film from the Department of Athletics, undated; AV5145 (Reel AV5145)
    This material is related to RG 41, Records of the Department of Athletics.
    Basketball.; Football.; New York University -- Sports
  - NYU vs. University of North Carolina, 1946-1947; AV5146 (Reel 5146)
  - NYU vs. University of Michigan, 1963; AV5147 (Reel AV5147)
  - NYU (football), circa 1940; AV5148; 1 film reels; 16 mm film (Reel AV5148)
    Black and white; Silent
  - NYU vs. Texas 1948 Reel 2, AV5149; 1 film reels; 16 mm film (Box 159, Reel AV5149 / Av_ref751)
  - NYU vs. St. Josephs MSG, 6 January 1961; AV5150; 1 film reels; 8 mm film (Box 159, Reel AV5150 / Av_ref752)
  - NYU vs. UMass 1st Round NCAA Philadelphia. 3/12/62, 1962; AV5151; 1 film reels; 8 mm film (Box 159, Reel AV5151 / Av_ref753)
    Basketball.
  - NYU vs. LaSalle 1962, AV5152; 1 film reels; 8 mm film (Box 159, Reel AV5152 / Av_ref754)
  - NYU Athletics Compilation (Videos #6-8), 1946-1962; AV5153; 1 film reels; 16 mm film (Reel AV5153)
    Games on this reel include: NYU vs. Cornell University; NYU vs. Rutgers, the State University of New Jersey, 1948; University of Cincinnati vs. St. Bonaventure University; NYU vs. the University of Massachusetts, NYU v. the University of Arkansas @ MSG, NYU v. University of Texas.
  - NYU Athletics Compilation (11-16), undated; AV5154; 1 film reels; 16 mm film (Reel AV5154)
  - NYU Athletics Compilation (17-21), undated; AV5155; 1 film reels; 16 mm film (Reel AV5155)
  - NYU Athletics Compilation (1-5), undated; AV5156; 1 film reels; 16 mm film (Reel AV5156)
    Physical/Technical
  - NYU Athletics Compilation (32-36), undated; AV5157; 1 film reels; 16 mm film (Reel AV5157)
  - NYU Athletics Compilation (22-26), undated; AV5158; 1 film reels; 16 mm film (Reel AV5158)
  - NYU Athletics Compilation (27-31), undated; AV5159; 1 film reels; 16 mm film (Reel AV5159)
  - The Secretary's Day, undated; AV5160; Agnew, Peter Lawrence, 1901-; Coronet Instructional Films; 1 film reels; Label reads: No. 143 [handwritten: 08632] Coronet Instructional Films Coronet Bldg, Chicago 1, Ill.
    History of Coronet Instructional Films
    Coronet Instructional Films were produced in the 1940s and 1950s to provide guidance for teenagers. The films were sold to schools and libraries. Most Coronet films were shot on Kodachrome but made and sold as black and white prints due to cost.
  - The Secretary Transcribes, 1947; AV5161; Coronet Instructional Films; 1 film reels; Label reads: No. 129 [handwritten: BW-C 4/25] Coronet Instructional Films Coronet Bldg, Chicago 1, Ill.
  - The Secretary Takes Dictation, 1947; AV5162; Coronet Instructional Films; 1 film reels; Label reads: No.128 [handwritten: BW C6918] Coronet Instructional Films Coronet Bldg, Chicago 1, Ill.
  - "Blacklist", 30 March 1964; AV5163-5164; 2 film reels; Both labels read: Plautus Productions, Inc. 105 East 106th Street, New York 29, NY TR6-8400. THE DEFENDERS Prod #84 "Blacklist" [handwritten: BLACK LIST NATAS PRINT #] Production element: Contrast print (Box 146, Reel 5163-5164, Box 147)
  - N.Y. Philharmonic Young People's Concert (Part I), undated; AV5165; CBS Television Network (Box 146, Reel 5165, Box 147)
    The University Archives does not have recordings of this content aside from this recording (labeled Part I).
  - Alumni Fun (Episode 8, Season 3), 15 January 1966; AV5166; Reeves Sound Studios; Columbia Broadcasting System, Inc.; 1 film reels; 16 mm
    Alumni Fun was a CBS game show that aired between 1963 and 1966. Alumni from colleges and universities across the United States competed to win money for scholarships. Each show featured two teams of three participants each; they answered questions in a variety of categories to receive points. Teams would continue in competition until defeated.
    This episode features NYU competing against the University of Colorado.
    University of Colorado; Lesueur, Laurence Edward, 1909-2003; Wilson, John D.; Vanderbur, Marilyn; Kramer, Stanley; Roach, Jim; Doman, Nicholas
  - "At Issue" (PA 220-2), 1965; AV5167-5175; WNET (Television station: New York, N.Y.); Du Art Film Laboratories; 38 film reels Reels stored in 9 film canisters.
  - [Unlabeled], undated; AV5167_1 (Box 163, Reel AV5167_1)
    Note on canister reads "Print"
  - [Unlabeled], undated; AV5167_2 (Box 163, Reel AV5167_2)
    Note on canister reads "Neg"
  - [Unlabeled], undated; AV5167_3 (Box 163, Reel AV5167_3)
    Note on canister reads "Mag"
  - [Unlabeled], undated; AV5168_1 (Box 161, Reel AV5168_1)
    Note on canister reads "Pix"
  - [Unlabeled], undated; AV5168_2 (Box 161, Reel AV5168_2)
  - [Unlabeled], undated; AV5168_3 (Box 161, Reel AV5168_3)
  - [Unlabeled], undated; AV5169_1 (Box 161, Reel AV5169_1)
  - [Unlabeled], undated; AV5169_2 (Box 161, Reel AV5169_2)
  - [Unlabeled], undated; AV5169_3 (Box 161, Reel AV5169_3)
  - [Unlabeled], undated; AV5169_4 (Box 161, Reel AV5169_4)
  - [Unlabeled], undated; AV5170_1; 16mm film (Box 79, Reel AV5170_1)
    New York University
  - [Unlabeled], undated; AV5170_2 (Box 163, Reel AV5170_2)
  - [Unlabeled], undated; AV5170_3 (Box 164, Reel AV5170_3)
  - [Unlabeled], undated; AV5170_4 (Box 164, Reel AV5170_4)
  - [Unlabeled], undated; AV5171_1 (Box 163, Reel AV5171_1)
  - [Unlabeled], undated; AV5171_2 (Box 163, Reel AV5171_2)
  - [Unlabeled], undated; AV5171_3 (Box 163, Reel AV5171_3)
  - [Unlabeled], undated; AV5171_4 (Box 163, Reel AV5171_4)
  - [Unlabeled], undated; AV5171_5 (Box 162, Reel AV5171_5)
  - [Unlabeled], undated; AV5171_6 (Box 162, Reel AV5171_6)
  - [Unlabeled], undated; AV5172_1 (Box 163, Reel AV5172_1)
  - [Unlabeled], undated; AV5172_2 (Box 163, Reel AV5172_2)
  - [Unlabeled], undated; AV5172_3 (Box 163, Reel AV5172_3)
  - [Unlabeled], undated; AV5172_4 (Box 164, Reel AV5172_4)
    Notes on canister read "Pic" and "Pix"
  - [Unlabeled], undated; AV5172_5 (Box 162, Reel AV5172_5)
  - [Unlabeled], undated; AV5173_1 (Box 161, Reel AV5173_1)
  - [Unlabeled], undated; AV5173_2 (Box 161, Reel AV5173_2)
  - [Unlabeled], undated; AV5173_3 (Box 161, Reel AV5173_3)
  - [Unlabeled], undated; AV5173_4 (Box 161, Reel AV5173_4)
  - [Unlabeled], undated; AV5173_5 (Box 161, Reel AV5173_5)
  - [Unlabeled], undated; AV5173_6 (Box 162, Reel AV5173_6)
  - [Unlabeled], undated; AV5173_7 (Box 162, Reel AV5173_7)
  - [Unlabeled], undated; AV5174_1 (Box 162, Reel AV5174_1)
  - [Unlabeled], undated; AV1574_2 (Box 162, Reel AV5174_2)
  - [Unlabeled], undated; AV5174_3 (Box 161, Reel AV5174_3)
  - [Unlabeled], undated; AV5174_4 (Box 161, Reel AV5174_4)
  - [Unlabeled], undated; AV5174_5 (Box 161, Reel AV5174_5)
    Note on canister reads "1.2% shrinkage"
  - [Unlabeled], undated; AV5174_6 (Box 161, Reel AV5174_6)
  - [Unlabeled], undated; AV5175_1 (Box 163, Reel AV5175_1)
  - [Unlabeled], undated; AV5175_2 (Box 163, Reel AV5175_2)
  - [Unlabeled], undated; AV5175_3 (Box 163, Reel AV5175_3)
  - [Unlabeled], undated; AV5175_4 (Box 163, Reel AV5175_4)
  - [Unlabeled], undated; AV5175_5 (Box 163, Reel AV5175_5)
  - [Unlabeled], undated; AV5175_6 (Box 162, Reel AV5175_6)
  - "The Emergence of Modern Philanthropy: The Rockefeller Story", 7 December 1999; AV5175; 1 VHS (Box 124, Cassette AV5175)
  - New Trustee Induction: Welcoming the Class of 2012, AV5176; 5 DVD-R (Box 124, Dvd AV5176 (1-5))
  - 2012 New Trustee Induction Ceremony DVDs, February 30, 2013; AV5177; 5 DVD-R (Box 124, Dvd AV5177 (1-5))
    These DVDs are related to RG 7.1: The Records of the Office of University Development and Alumni Relations (Office of Gift Administration).
  - "Where We Stand: The Campaign for New York University School of Law", September 2005; cuid18372 (Box Electronic Records, Item UA_AV_ER_1)
  - 2014 New Trustee Induction Ceremony, February 18, 2015; AV5178; 4 DVD-R (Box 124, Dvd AV5178 (1-5))
  - Bobst Atrium, Peres Convocation, 1985-10-21; cuid2 (Box 27, Reel 1090, Box Shared University Archives 117, Item 10)
  - NYU vs. Notre Dame (Basketball), 1940-02-10; AV2987 (Box 81, Reel AV2987, Box Digitized Access Files, File UAAV_AV2987)
    The first half of a basketball game between New York University and Notre Dame.
    Format: 16mm film
  - NYU Office of the President, La Peitra, Interview: Sir Harold at Temple/Garden Statuary/Garden Walks, Tape 6, 1987-07-30; cuid3290 (Box 58, Cassette AV_ref279, Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid3290)
    Format: 3/4" Umatic, Duration: 30 min.
  - NYU Office of the President, La Peitra, Lemon Garden Pasqualina, Dr. Brademas asking questions, Tape 7, 1987-07-30; cuid3291 (Box 58, Cassette AV_ref285, Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid3291)
  - NYU Office of the President, La Peitra, Conversation Dr. Brademus and Sir Harold, Tape 8, 1987-07-30; cuid3292 (Box 58, Cassette AV_ref285, Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid3292)
  - NYU Office of the President, La Peitra, Conversation Dr. Brademus and Sir Harold (cont), Tape 9, 1987-07-30; cuid3293 (Box 58, Cassette AV_ref288, Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid3293)
  - NYU Office of the President, La Peitra, Tape 10, 1987-07-30; cuid3294 (Box 58, Cassette AV_ref291, Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid3293)
  - NYU Office of the President, La Peitra, Conversations Brademas/Sir Harold, Tape 17, 1987-07-30; cuid3295 (Box 58, Cassette AV_ref309, Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid3295)
  - NYU Office of the President, La Peitra, Conversations, Brademas/Sir Harold, Tape 18, 1987-07-30; cuid3296 (Box 58, Cassette AV_ref315, Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid3296)
  - Inauguration Dinner: L. Jay Oliva, 20 November 1991; AV2196 (Box 57, Cassette AV2196, Cassette AV2197, Box Digitized Access Files, File AV2196)
    Format: 1/8" audiocassette, Duration 90 min. Note: Two cassettes. One is a master recording, the other is a duplicate.
  - Tour of Bobst's Instructional Materials Center, undated; AV5017 (Box 156, Reel AV5017)
    Format: 1/2" open reel video; Duration: 30 minutes; Transfer Technician Notes: "This tape contains only about 4 minutes of content. All the video content is very unstable and has poor vertical hold. Most of the content has extremely low audio levels, but the audio could not be raised without clipping the louder audio in the last segment. Headswitch error in underscan"
  - Inside Bobst Library Video Footage, undated; AV5018 (Box 156, Reel AV5018, Reel AV5022, Reel AV5023)
    Format: 1/2" Open Reel Video; Duration: 30 min; Transfer Technician Notes AV5018: "First eight and a half minutes include audio but no video. This portion appears to be equipment testing. Occasional audio pops and distortion during this segment. Video is identical to that as found on several other tapes in this collection (inside Bobst Library), and features overdubbed music. Frequent dropouts and mild image echo occur throughout. Audio has inherent crackle from original sources. Head switch error visible during portion with video."
    Transfer Technician Notes AV5022: "This tape has content similar to AV5023, with some identical video. Both of these tapes are without program audio. Video plays mostly well throughout. Head switch error visible in underscan. Occasional crash records require manual adjustment to vertical framing. Other inherent edits result in luma banding. Occasional tracking errors following inherent edits are mitigated as best possible. Occasional dropouts, tape wear, and tape damage occur throughout. Occasional mild ghosting and bearding throughout. Loud audio buzzing throughout."
    Transfer Technician Notes AV5023: "This tape has content similar to AV5022, with some identical video. Both of these tapes are without program audio. Video plays mostly well throughout, and consists of several segments that repeat multiple times. Frequent crash records throughout, with some segments of extended static. Other inherent edits result in luma banding. Occasional dropouts, tape wear, and tape damage occur throughout. Occasional mild ghosting and bearding throughout. Head switch error visible in underscan. Audio hiss throughout."
  - Lecture on the Use of a Medical Library Database System, undated; AV5019 (Box 156, Reel AV5016, Reel AV5019, Reel AV5020)
    Format: 1/2" open reel video; Duration: 30 minutes; Transfer Technician Notes AV5016: "Tape contains two segments of content. The first is just black video with ambient audio of people testing the video equipment. The second is a lecture on the use of the medical library database system, which is very unstable and has poor vertical hold. headswitch error in underscan."
    Transfer Technician Notes AV5019: "Tape contains a lecture on the use of the medical library database system, which is very unstable and has poor vertical hold. headswitch error in underscan."
    Transfer Technician Notes AV5020: "Tape contains two segments of content. The first has stable video and appears to be shots of the NYU library offices. The second is a lecture on the use of the medical library database system, which is very unstable and has poor vertical hold. Headswitch error in underscan."
  - First N.Y.S. Conf. on the Victims of Alcoholism (Workshop), AV5021 (Box 53, Reel AV5021)
    Format: 1/2" open reel video; Duration: 60 min; Transfer Technician Notes: "Entirety of tape suffers from a constant control track error. Multiple TBCs were tested to obtain the best capture possible. Content suffers from persistent skew error affecting the entire frame, as well as flagging and image jitter throughout. Aside from these anomalies, there are occasional instances of minor dropouts and tape wear. Occasional inherent exposure adjustments. Audio distortion is inherent to the original recording."
  - Ellesmere Island Trip, Undated; AV5024 (Box 155, Reel AV5024)
    Original format: 1/2 inch open reel video; Transfer Technician Notes: "Much of the content on this tape is of a projected film. Inherent dirt, dust, and scratches appear on the film, and the projection results in inherent flicker throughout. Other effects are inherent to the film, notably frame speed variations. Aside from these artifacts, the tape plays remarkably well. Occasional tape wear and damage occurs, with mild recurring dropouts. Edge wear or a high head switch error is visible in underscan. Occasional mild audio distortion is inherent to the original recording."
  - Spilhaus (Tape 1), AV70 (Box 8, Reel AV70, Box Digitized Access Files, File AV70)
  - Spilhaus (Tape 2), AV71 (Box 8, Reel AV71, Box Digitized Access Files, File AV71)
  - New York University Men's Glee Club in Concert, LP, 1968-03 (Box Shared University Archives 079)
  - NYU Glee Club: "The Palisades", "The Subway", 1940 (Box Shared University Archives 079)
  - Commencement 1997 -- Access Copy, May 15, 1997 (Box Shared University Archives 115, Dvd 12:20)